hey guys I'm professor Dave and I want
to tell you about chemistry
what is chemistry why should we
know about it
chemistry is the study of what matter is
made of and how it changes
it's important to know because it describes
everything around us
every material, almost every process. if
we truly want to understand how our
bodies work
how diseases operate, how to cure them
which foods are nutritious and which are not
we must learn chemistry. unless you
fundamentally understand molecules
all you can do is repeat things you've
heard. but how do you know for you heard
is right?
if you know chemistry you can compare
what someone says to how you know that
molecules behave
if there is a glaring contradiction you
can easily reject false information
and you won't be taken advantage of for
someone else's personal gain. we should
be able to think critically like this in
every avenue of life
be it health, politics or otherwise. with
this general chemistry series
I have two goals. one is to help high
school and undergraduate students taking
their first chemistry course.
please use these tutorials to supplement
your lectures in any way that is helpful
to you
but because this is introductory
material and given that chemistry is the
central science
this general chemistry series also meant
for anyone who wants to learn science
with no prior knowledge and for any
reason. I will break down concepts as
simply as possible
so that anyone can learn them. there will be
moments where we go over practice
problems
that are more geared towards students in
a class, but feel free to learn these too.
because the predictive power of
mathematics is what proves the
legitimacy of our science
if you're watching this clip and intend
to view the entire series
please click on the general chemistry
playlist under the Professor dave home page
to view in the suggested order. when we
check our comprehension after lesson
feel free to pause the clip so you have
plenty of time to think
before I tell you the answer. if you need
to watch a clip more than once to fully
understand it
that's okay. and if you have any
questions about what you've learned
feel free to email me
enjoy your newfound knowledge